answers.com 2005-05-27

# Answers.com - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Because your privacy is important to us, Answers.com Privacy Policy is based on the following principle: respect and protect the privacy of our users. The Privacy Policy explains how Answers.com adheres to this principle in order to serve you best. 

This policy only addresses services from our servers. Other websites, such as those we link to or co-brand with, may have their own policies. 

  1. **What We Track**  
When you use Answers.com or any of the software options for access to Answers.com, a random number ("User ID") is assigned to you and we know you simply by that User ID. We collect data about user activity only in aggregate form in an effort to assess and react to general usage trends (frequency, common topics, peak usage times, etc.). 

Answers.com is not spyware; we do not run any background processes that report back to us information about your software or hardware configuration, or your web browsing or purchasing habits. 

Answers.com is not a "keylogger". The only keystroke that Answers.com is reporting to our servers is the Alt-Click that you perform on text to look it up. This function is only activated when you hold down the Alt key and Click on a word or phrase. _When_ you Alt-Click on a word, we perform contextual analysis on the Alt-Clicked word by sending other words surrounding the Alt-Clicked word to our server so that we can deliver the best page for your query. For example, if you Alt-Click on "Jordan", we return different pages if the word before is "Michael" or if the word after is "River." This surrounding contextual data is used only to help clarify your target word and is not used for any sales or marketing purposes. Answers.com does not communicate with our servers unless you initiate it. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

The Usage Data (i.e. non-personally identifiable data) we track about our users may be used and shared with third parties on an aggregate basis (e.g., our corporate customers or third-party content providers) in order to provide a better or more customer-focused service to our users. 

  2. **How We Track It**  
Answers.com uses either cookies and/or registry settings on your computer to store user information. A "cookie" is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service and to better understand how people interact with us. You can use Answers.com even if cookies are disabled, but this may impact our ability to adapt Answers.com according to your preferences. 
  3. **Information Sharing**  
We do not rent or sell your personally identifying information to other companies or individuals, unless we have your consent. We may share such information in any of the following limited circumstances:
    * We have your consent.
    * We conclude that we are required by law or have a good faith belief that access, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of GuruNet, its users or the public.
  
In the event of a transfer of ownership of GuruNet Corporation,such as acquisition by or merger with another company, we will provide notice before any personally identifying information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 
  4. **Changes to This Privacy Statement**  
Answers.com may amend this policy from time to time. If we make any major changes in the way your personally identifiable data may be used, we will notify you by posting the new text on our website. 

**Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Support.

For more information on protecting your privacy on-line, please see the following sites:

**Center for Democracy and Technology**  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/>

**Electronic Privacy Information Center**  
<http://epic.org/>

**Electronic Frontier Foundation**  
<http://www.eff.org/>
